RG 062:078, Town of Mansfield
Connecticut State Library
Town of Mansfield records
1810-1950
bulk, 1810-1917
Connecticut State Library
Mansfield (Conn.)
19 cubic feet
Adminstrative, election, school, and tax records for the town of Mansfield. There are also aerial photographs, 1950.
RG062_078
Multiple
Historical Note
The town of Mansfield was incorporated in October 1702 and was taken from Windham.
Scope and Content
Adminstrative, election, school, and tax records for the town of Mansfield. There are also aerial photographs, 1950.
Index Terms
Alternate Creators:
Connecticut. Justice of the Peace (Mansfield)
Subjects:
Public welfare -- Connecticut -- Mansfield; Tax assessment -- Connecticut -- Mansfield -- Registers; Taxation -- Connecticut -- Mansfield -- Registers; Local taxation -- Connecticut -- Mansfield -- Registers; Property tax -- Connecticut -- Mansfield -- Registers; School enrollment -- Connecticut -- Mansfield -- Statistics; Voting registers -- Connecticut -- Mansfield; Elections -- Connecticut -- Mansfield -- Statistics; Voting -- Connecticut -- Mansfield -- Statistics; Justices of the peace -- Connecticut -- Mansfield; Aerial photographs -- Connecticut -- Mansfield
Places:
Mansfield (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence
Restrictions on Access
Some of these records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1810-1950; bulk 1810-1917
  - T000246
    - Tax abstracts, 1819-1862 (Box Box 1-2)
    - Rate books, 1812-1866 (Box Box 3)
    - Highway rate books, 1848, 1879-1884 (Box Box 3)
    - Grand lists, 1810-1913 (Box Box 4)
      scattered
    - Lists of taxes collected, circa 1870-1898 (Box Box 4)
    - Tax liens and tax lien releases, 1873-1912 (Box Box 4)
    - Bonds and notes, 1791-1903 (Box Box 4)
    - Bank reports of stockholders, circa 1860 (Box Box 4)
    - Abatements and "Doings of the Board of Relief, 1816-1912 (Box Box 5)
    - Treasurer and Town Deposit Fund records, undated (Box Box 6)
    - Records and appointments of overseers, undated (Box Box 6)
    - Militia records, undated (Box Box 7)
    - Annual statements of corporations, vital records abstracts, undated (Box Box 7)
    - Railroad and highway records, 1807-1908 (Box Box 7)
    - Crow bounty certificates, 1834-1835 (Box Box 7)
    - Assorted records and fragments, undated (Box Box 7)
    - Town meeting minutes, calls, and votes, 1823-1911 (Box Box 8)
    - School returns, 1847-1906 (Box Boxes 9-10)
    - School records, including reports, assessments, financial records, minutes of district meetings, 1823-1917 (Box Box 10)
    - School registers, assessments, vote for 1818 state Constitution; vote tally, list of voters, 1818-1917 (Box Box 11)
    - Oaths of office, petitions, election returns, statements of candidate expenses, certificates for religious dissenters who do not want to pay society tax, 1816-1896 (Box Box 12)
    - Lists of electors, freemen admitted, and vote returns, 1821-1910 (Box Boxes 12-14)
    - Bills, indentures, petitions, receipts, reports, survey of highways, children bound out, church records, warnings out, justice of the peace records, correspondence, circa 1820-1900 (Box Boxes 15-16)
    - Tax abstracts, 1863-1872; 15 volumes
      - First society, 1853, 1854, 1861, 1863, 1864, 1865, 1866, 1867, 1872 (Box Box 17)
      - Second society, 1861, 1862, 1866, 1867, 1868, 1872 (Box Box 17)
    - Voter lists, 1860-1910 (Box Box 18)
      On oversize shelving.
  - 2007-023
    - List of males in North Parish, 1891 (Box Shared box)
  - 2008-030
    - Index map to aerial photographs, 1950
      Shows the area of town covered by each aerial photograph.
    - Aerial photographs, 1950; 58 photographs
      Arranged numerically 1-54. There are also photographs numbered 30A, 31A and 32A.
      The number of photographs covering the town total 57. There is one additional unidentified photograph that is probably a sample provided by the firm that created the photographs.
      Each photograph is approximately 35 x 35 inches and cut into halves. Each half is mounted on a panel. In some cases the panels are attached to each other but in other cases they are not. Both panels are labeled to ensure that they can be matched. For example, the left panel of Map 1 is labeled "Map 1-a" and the right side "Map 1-b".
      The Town of Mansfield retains 10 x 10 inch prints of these aerial photographs.